<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mindset on boblbobl</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/tags/mindset/</link><description>Recent content in Mindset on boblbobl</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 07:56:18 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boblbobl.com/tags/mindset/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Revisiting My Workplace Manifesto</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/2020/10/04/revisiting-my-workplace-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 07:56:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boblbobl.com/2020/10/04/revisiting-my-workplace-manifesto/</guid><description>&lt;p>In July 2013, I posted my workplace manifesto on a Tumblr blog I had back then. It was a list of five priorities I wanted for a current – or future workplace; some of them felt a bit far-fetched or maybe even utopian, so how do they stack up today?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-manifesto">The Manifesto&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Without further ado here is the manifesto:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Be able to work on projects that excite you!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Be able to put in the hours to finish the project and NOT be bound by the project’s price-tag.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Be able to work when and where you are motivated, even if this is at nine o’clock in the evening or in a café or at home.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Be able to choose the right technology for the project, and not the other way around.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Be able to work with the right set of tools on the job and not the workplace “default” that has been decided by IT or any other who have no idea of what works best for you.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>When I wrote this manifesto, I worked as a consultant and solution architect at Creuna, working on various enterprise solutions often limited by its contract. I was frustrated about the limitations to how many hours I could spend on a specific project, dictated with a fixed-price-contract, and the types of projects I had to work on; not all of them motivated me. I worked on predominantly CMS-solutions, so new projects were described as either a &lt;a href="https://www.sitecore.com/" >Sitecore&lt;/a> – or &lt;a href="https://www.episerver.com/" >Episerver&lt;/a> project, not by the site’s actual goal. Also, I had not yet become a dad, so the restrictions of a traditional nine-to-five job felt very limiting.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>