<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dashboard on boblbobl</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/tags/dashboard/</link><description>Recent content in Dashboard on boblbobl</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 10:18:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boblbobl.com/tags/dashboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Planning in the Dark</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/2021/01/15/planning-in-the-dark/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 10:18:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boblbobl.com/2021/01/15/planning-in-the-dark/</guid><description>&lt;p>Why are we so afraid to show temporary or early drafts of plans to our teams, and why are we so obsessed with planning reveals at kick-offs?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know, but it seems to be our ways-of-working when it comes to planning, road-mapping, or defining objectives. We have this idea that planning only involves the product owner/lead/manager and relevant stakeholders. We tend to have a non-transparent process of what the quarterly - or half-year plans will look like until we do the final unveil at the next &amp;ldquo;kick-off&amp;rdquo; with the rest of the team.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making OKR Work for Small Development Teams</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/2020/09/28/making-okr-work-for-small-development-teams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 09:48:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boblbobl.com/2020/09/28/making-okr-work-for-small-development-teams/</guid><description>&lt;p>A current trend in our industry is to formulate your goals as Objectives and Key Results (or OKR). However, there are a few challenges when implementing OKR, especially on a team level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post is an overview of how we use (or misuse) OKR on a small development team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To give you a little context, our team consists of 3 developers and a product owner (that is I). We have a daily stand-up every day at noon and do refinement session once a week. Everyone (including myself) are attending all team meetings (including retrospectives). We use a Kanban board to support the prioritization of work and tracking progress. We do not use sprints or commit to work that we need to deliver within a specific deadline; instead, we communicate expected delivery dates based on our lead time.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>