<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on boblbobl</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on boblbobl</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 11:11:10 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boblbobl.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I Hate Screen Protectors</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/2021/05/01/i-hate-screen-protectors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 11:11:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boblbobl.com/2021/05/01/i-hate-screen-protectors/</guid><description>I just bought a new iPad and of course I had to install a screen protector. Why wouldn’t I? A brand new iPad needs to be protected, right?
The case for the Screen Protector I bought the best screen protector money can buy, Paperlike. Paperlike is excellent for when using the Apple Pencil; it gives a bit of friction to the pencil to feel (and sound) a bit like paper when drawing or writing on the screen.</description></item><item><title>Planning in the Dark</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/2021/01/15/planning-in-the-dark/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 10:18:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boblbobl.com/2021/01/15/planning-in-the-dark/</guid><description>Why are we so afraid to show temporary or early drafts of plans to our teams, and why are we so obsessed with planning reveals at kick-offs?
I don&amp;rsquo;t know, but it seems to be our ways-of-working when it comes to planning, road-mapping, or defining objectives. We have this idea that planning only involves the product owner/lead/manager and relevant stakeholders. We tend to have a non-transparent process of what the quarterly - or half-year plans will look like until we do the final unveil at the next &amp;ldquo;kick-off&amp;rdquo; with the rest of the team.</description></item><item><title>Making a ZX Spectrum Game - Part 2 - The Initial Prototype in Sinclair Basic</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/2020/11/17/making-a-zx-spectrum-game-part-2-the-initial-prototype-in-sinclair-basic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 10:45:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boblbobl.com/2020/11/17/making-a-zx-spectrum-game-part-2-the-initial-prototype-in-sinclair-basic/</guid><description>Now it is time to write some actual code. As I described in a previous post, I want to create an initial prototype directly in Sinclair BASIC, which will allow me to test out the gameplay of the Awakeman game on a ZX Spectrum.
It has been a while since I coded in BASIC. My first job as a developer was to create small programs in Visual Basic for Applications (VBA), so building this prototype will also act as a refresher to BASIC.</description></item><item><title>Making a ZX Spectrum Game - Part 1 - My Development Setup</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/2020/11/10/making-a-zx-spectrum-game-part-1-my-development-setup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 14:59:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boblbobl.com/2020/11/10/making-a-zx-spectrum-game-part-1-my-development-setup/</guid><description>With side-projects like this one, I tend to leave the project unchanged for weeks. Therefore, I have found it good practice to write down the explicit details about my development setup; it makes it a lot easier to return to a project set on pause for a while.
As a general rule-of-thumb, my development setup has to be as platform-agnostic as possible. I think this is good practice. It allows a broader audience to follow-along when doing tutorials like this one, and it makes me independent from whether my next primary computer would be a Mac or a Windows PC.</description></item><item><title>Making a ZX Spectrum Game - Part 0 - Defining the Project</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/2020/11/04/making-a-zx-spectrum-game-part-0-defining-the-project/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 16:24:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boblbobl.com/2020/11/04/making-a-zx-spectrum-game-part-0-defining-the-project/</guid><description>For sentimental reasons, I recently bought a ZX Spectrum from a dear colleague, but what to do with it? I could play games from my childhood, but why not make my own?! The Speccy, after all, was what created a generation of bedroom coders. Because of the 8-bit hardware limitations, this would be an excellent opportunity to flex my programming muscle, something I do not get to do all that often.</description></item><item><title>Revisiting My Workplace Manifesto</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/2020/10/04/revisiting-my-workplace-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 07:56:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boblbobl.com/2020/10/04/revisiting-my-workplace-manifesto/</guid><description>In July 2013, I posted my workplace manifesto on a Tumblr blog I had back then. It was a list of five priorities I wanted for a current – or future workplace; some of them felt a bit far-fetched or maybe even utopian, so how do they stack up today?
The Manifesto Without further ado here is the manifesto:
Be able to work on projects that excite you! Be able to put in the hours to finish the project and NOT be bound by the project’s price-tag.</description></item><item><title>Making OKR Work for Small Development Teams</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/2020/09/28/making-okr-work-for-small-development-teams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 09:48:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boblbobl.com/2020/09/28/making-okr-work-for-small-development-teams/</guid><description>A current trend in our industry is to formulate your goals as Objectives and Key Results (or OKR). However, there are a few challenges when implementing OKR, especially on a team level.
This post is an overview of how we use (or misuse) OKR on a small development team.
To give you a little context, our team consists of 3 developers and a product owner (that is I). We have a daily stand-up every day at noon and do refinement session once a week.</description></item><item><title>Make Your Presentations Fun</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/2020/09/23/make-your-presentations-fun/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 09:52:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boblbobl.com/2020/09/23/make-your-presentations-fun/</guid><description>When asked to do a presentation about something or the other, I struggle to find the motivation from time-to-time. Here are a few tips on what I do when preparing for a talk.
To quickly summarize, these are the steps I go through:
Somehow make the subject exciting Challenge myself Think about the presentation; can I make this entertaining to the participants Make the Subject Exciting Often I am asked to make a presentation about something I know by heart, which is great because this means that I probably have a presentation already on the subject tucked away somewhere that I can reuse.</description></item><item><title>Seeking Speaking Opportunities</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/2020/09/22/seeking-speaking-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 13:14:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boblbobl.com/2020/09/22/seeking-speaking-opportunities/</guid><description>I work as a Lead Platform Architect at the LEGO Group, where I am the acting product owner of our analytics platform supporting the digital consumer space. In my spare time, I like to work on old retro 8-bit computers.
I have some experience speaking internally and externally. I would, however, like to sharpen that tool even further. Therefore, I am seeking speaking opportunities outside of my work, be it conferences or local events (virtual or in-person).</description></item><item><title>My 2020 New Years Resolution</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/2020/01/02/my-2020-new-years-resolution/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:52:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boblbobl.com/2020/01/02/my-2020-new-years-resolution/</guid><description>Although I’m not a big fan of New Year’s resolutions, I like the idea of a new year = new habits, so here are mine:
Start blogging again Quit social media and YouTube Start lifelogging …and here is why:
Make a Personal Blog I used to write more in my previous jobs as a developer and solution architect but stopped about six years ago when I started working in my current position at LEGO.</description></item></channel></rss>