<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Presentation on boblbobl</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/tags/presentation/</link><description>Recent content in Presentation on boblbobl</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 09:52:23 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boblbobl.com/tags/presentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Make Your Presentations Fun</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/2020/09/23/make-your-presentations-fun/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 09:52:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boblbobl.com/2020/09/23/make-your-presentations-fun/</guid><description>&lt;p>When asked to do a presentation about something or the other, I struggle to find the motivation from time-to-time. Here are a few tips on what I do when preparing for a talk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To quickly summarize, these are the steps I go through:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Somehow make the subject exciting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Challenge myself&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Think about the presentation; can I make this entertaining to the participants&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="make-the-subject-exciting">Make the Subject Exciting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Often I am asked to make a presentation about something I know by heart, which is great because this means that I probably have a presentation already on the subject tucked away somewhere that I can reuse. On the other hand, this means that I probably have talked about the subject so often that I might come off sounding a bit uninterested and unexcited when I give yet another talk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seeking Speaking Opportunities</title><link>https://boblbobl.com/2020/09/22/seeking-speaking-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 13:14:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boblbobl.com/2020/09/22/seeking-speaking-opportunities/</guid><description>&lt;p>I work as a Lead Platform Architect at the LEGO Group, where I am the acting product owner of our analytics platform supporting the digital consumer space. In my spare time, I like to work on old retro 8-bit computers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have some experience speaking internally and externally. I would, however, like to sharpen that tool even further. Therefore, I am seeking speaking opportunities outside of my work, be it conferences or local events (virtual or in-person).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>